Finding Aid for Ypsilanti (Mich.: Township) records, 1827-1923
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ypsilanti (Mich.: Township) records 1827-1923
Ypsilanti (Mich.: Township)
12 volumes and ca. 30 items (in 1 box), 1 outsize folder, and 1 microfilm reel.
85862 Cb 2; Cb Outsize; Cb Microcopy
Township meeting minutes; highway commissioners, 1827-1831; assessment rolls, 1832-1838; also miscellaneous school records, districts 1 and 5; and election record books, 1827-1860.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record came from multiple sources. In 1938, Edward D. Foster (donor no. 382 ) donated the bulk of the early records; in June 1942, Mrs. Leona Weaver (donor no. 1701 ) donated the records of school district no. 1; Wystan Stevens (donor no. 4452 ) donated miscellaneous other materials.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Ypsilanti Township is located in eastern Washtenaw County, Michigan.
Township in eastern Washtenaw County, Michiagn. The record group consists of a scattering of early nineteenth century Ypsilanti Township records, mainly in the period of 1827 to 1838. These include minutes of township meetings and of the highway commission, and assessment rolls. Another portion of the record group consists of records of individual school districts.
Subjects:
Roads--Michigan--Ypsilanti (Township); Schools--Michigan--Ypsilanti (Township); Ypsilanti (Mich.: Township)
- Township Records
  - Township meetings, 1828-1833, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Inspectors of elections, 1827-1833, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Highway Commission, 1827-1831, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Assessment rolls, 1832 and 1834-1838, 6 volumes (Box 1)
  - Agreement re: discontinuance of road, 1831 (Box 1)
  - School records
    - District No. 1 records, 1834-1905, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - District No. 5 records, 1837, 1876 and 1878-1923, 1 volumes and 1 folder (Box 1)
      (see also oversize folder)
    - District No. 8 records, 1837, 1 item in outsize folder (Folder Cb)
  - Election book, 1827-1860 (Reel 1)
    (1 reel of positive microfilm: CB Micro)